Carl Hildebrandt

Ph.D. Candidate, University of Virginia

85 Engineer's Way Charlottesville, VA hildebrandt.carl@virginia.edu https://hildebrandt-carl.com

USA, 22903

My research focuses on the intersection of autonomous systems and software testing. My research delves deep into ways for creating, executing, and better understanding test suites that consider software, hardware, and physical world interactions. Outside academia, I'm an athlete and adventurer, with achievements like summiting Kilimanjaro and competing in the world's largest ultramarathon.

Education

2018 – **University of Virginia**, USA

Ph.D. Computer Science Advisor: Dr. Sebastian Elbaum Lab: LESS (less-lab-uya.github.io)

2013 – 2016 University of Pretoria, South Africa

B.Eng. in Computer Engineering

Experience

2018 – Research Assistant, LESS Lab, University of Virginia (less-lab-uva.github.io)

2022 - 2022 Graduate Research Intern, Raytheon BBN, Boston (www.rtx.com)

2017 – 2018 Research Assistant, Nimbus Lab, University of Nebraska (nimbus.unl.edu)

Honors & Awards

External

2020 Distinguished Artifact Award

Feasible and Stressful Trajectory Generation for Mobile Robots (ISSTA)

2018 Best Paper Award on Safety, Security, and Rescue Robotics

Fire-Aware Planning of Aerial Trajectories and Ignitions (IROS)

Internal

2023 All-University Graduate Teaching Award

The University of Virginia - Office of Graduate and Postdoctoral affairs

2022 Graduate Teaching Award

The University of Virginia - Annual Computer Science Department End-of-Year Awards

2021 Best Poster Design

The University of Virginia - Computer Science Research Symposium

2020 **Best Presentation**

The University of Virginia - Computer Science Virtual Research Symposium

Publications

- Carl Hildebrandt, Meriel von Stein, and Sebastian Elbaum, "PhysCov: Physical Test Coverage for Autonomous Vehicles," in *Proceedings of the 32nd ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA)*, ACM, 2023
- Carl Hildebrandt, Wen Ying, Seongkook Heo, and Sebastian Elbaum, "Mimicking Real Forces on a UAV Through a Haptic Suit," in 2023 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE, 2023
- Carl Hildebrandt, Meriel von Stein, Trey Woodlief, and Sebastian Elbaum, "Preparing Software Engineers to Develop Robot Systems," in 2022 IEEE/ACM 44th International Conference on Software Engineering: Software Engineering Education and Training (ICSE-SEET), IEEE, 2022
- Carl Hildebrandt, and Sebastian Elbaum, "World-in-the-Loop Simulation for Autonomous Systems Validation," in 2021 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE, 2021, pp. 10 912–10 919
- Carl Hildebrandt, Sebastian Elbaum, Nicola Bezzo, and Matthew B Dwyer, "Feasible and stressful trajectory generation for mobile robots," in *Proceedings of the 29th ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA)*, 2020, pp. 349–362 (Distinguished Artifact Award)
- Carl Hildebrandt, Sebastian Elbaum, and Nicola Bezzo, "Blending kinematic and software models for tighter reachability analysis," in 2020 IEEE/ACM 42nd International Conference on Software Engineering: New Ideas and Emerging Results (ICSE-NIER), IEEE, 2020, pp. 33–36
- Evan Beachly, Carrick Detweiler, Sebastian Elbaum, Brittany Duncan, **Carl Hildebrandt**, Dirac Twidwell, and Craig Allen, "Fire-aware planning of aerial trajectories and ignitions," in 2018 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), IEEE, 2018, pp. 685–692 (**Best Paper Award**)

Patents

Carl Hildebrandt, Jefferson Griscavage, Victor Aquino, Melony Bennis, and Tien Comlekoglu, Vuetech Health Innovations LLC, "Systems and Methods for Safety, Security and Well-Being of Individuals", Patent No. 11282367

Talks

- Carl Hildebrandt "PhysCov: Physical Test Coverage for Autonomous Vehicles", International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis, July 19th
- Carl Hildebrandt "Preparing Software En- gineers to Develop Robot Systems", International Conference on Software Engineering: Software Engineering Education and Training, May 25th
- Carl Hildebrandt "World-in-the-Loop Simulation for Autonomous Systems Validation", International Conference on Robotics and Automation, May 30th
- Carl Hildebrandt "Feasible and Stressful Trajectory Generation for Mobile Robots", International Conference on Software Engineering, July 7th

Carl Hildebrandt "Blending Kinematic and Software Models for Tighter Reachability Analysis", International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis, July 21st

Community Service

2022	Artifact Reviewer, IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE).
2022	Graduate Student Council, The University of Virginia, Computer Science Department (CSGSG).
2022	Paper Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation Society (ICRA)
2021	Student Volunteer, IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE)

Teaching

2022	Supporting instructor, Robotics for Software Engineers , The University of Virginia
2021	Lab Designer and Guest Lecturer, Robotics for Software Engineers, The University of Virginia
2020	Lab Designer and Teaching Assistant, Robotics for Software Engineers, The University of Virginia
2016	Head Teaching Assistant, Data Structures and Algorithms in Java, The University of Pretoria
2015	Head Teaching Assistant, Program Design in C++ , The University of Pretoria
2015	Teaching Assistant, Data Structures and Algorithms in Java, The University of Pretoria
2014	Teaching Assistant, Introduction to Programming in C, The University of Pretoria

Skills

Licences:	Commercial drone	license for small	unmanned aircraft systems

Advanced: Python, C++, ROS, Shell Scripting, LaTeX, Quadrotors, Ubuntu, Windows, MacOS

Experienced: C, Java, Solidworks, Keras, Tensorflow, Unity, Control Theory, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Odroid

Proficient: Lua, C#, Assembly, HTML, CSS, Javascript, ONNX, FPGA, Soldering, Digital Logic

Achievements

2019	National Club Field Hockey Champions - The University of Virginia
2017	Half Iron Man - South Africa
2017	Comrades Ultra Marathon - South Africa
2016	Summited Kilimanjaro - Tanzania
2012	National u18B Field Hockey Team - South Africa